# Brian E. Mallen

**UX/UI** Designer







## Summary

Former small business executive turned designer, focused on crafting better user experiences through problem-solving and detailed analysis. Able to take an idea from vision to concept to production, using full array of design skills including user research, wireframing, prototyping, user testing, HiFi mockups, and more.

# **Experience**

### **UX/UI** Designer

LovetoKnow Media

10/2020 - Present

- Working in a remote environment in collaboration with engineering & product teams to define experiences throughout the user journey.
- Refine the brand's digital design system and component library
- Collaborate with stakeholders, including team members and Product Manager to efficiently identify and prioritize research opportunities.

### UI/UX Designer

PlateRate 06/2020 - Present

- Design UI & UX in collaboration with engineering & design teams using Scrum framework.
- Conduct user research to assist redesign of a responsive application.
- Implement style guide & produce aesthetically rich user interface designs.

#### Design Consultant

NAMI NJ 03/2020 - Present

- Create graphic designs for the organization's website, programs, and events.
- Modify and update designs as per request by the Associate Director and Communications Manager.

### **Product Design Apprentice**

Bloc by Thinkful

09/2019 - 04/2020

- Learn industry best practice and design process standards with a focus on UX Research, Visual Design, and Front-End Development.
- Complete 500+ hours of project-based work under the mentorship of three accomplished senior design professionals.

#### **Assistant Director**

Eagle's Landing Day Camp & Events

09/2012 - 08/2019

- Executive member of 200+ employee business. Responsibilities included staff training, operations, program development, and more.
- Design and implement paper and digital media including website redesigns, graphics, and display material.

### **Skills**

#### Design

User Research, Design & Content Strategy, User Interface, Web & Mobile Design, User Stories & Flows, Prototyping, User Testing, Wireframing, Mockups, Branding

#### Software

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, XD, Sketch, Invision, Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Interpersonal

Leadership, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Communication, Conflict Resolution, Autonomy

### **Education**

#### Bloc

Product Design Apprenticeship 2020

### **Rutgers University**

Bachelors of Sociology 2012